Okojie Eugene

88 Guinness Coat Mansell Street E18AE London 00442076809265 00447774176886 00491779740649 lotukpashan@yahoo.co.uk

Personal Profile:

Nine years working IT experience as Systems administrator, Software tester and Software Engineer. Analytical, meticulous and passionate about testing. Self motivated, adaptable and conscientious manual tester with automation software testing experience.

Good communications skills and good customer's relations skills. Appreciate the value of team work, level headed and can work independently to achieve set goals and objectives in line with defined scope and agreed time scale.

Education:

Aug 2009 – Oct 2012	National University of Ireland Galway Software Engineering and Database Technology Master of Science (M.sc)					
Dec 2012	ISTQB Certified Agile Tester Certificate in Software Testing, ISQL GmbH –Internationa Software Quality Institute Erlangen Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 6 Programmer					
Sept 2010						
Nov 2008	ISTQB Foundation Certificate in Software Testing, ISQL GmbH –International Software Quality Institute Erlangen					
Feb 2002 – May 2002	Grundig Academy, Nuremberg Germany ANSI C/C++ programming Certificate					
Oct 2001— Aug 2002	University of Applied .Sciences Georg-Simon Ohm, Nuremberg Germany; Software Engineering and Informatics Postgraduate Diploma.					
Oct 1986—Jul 1991	University of Benin, Nigeria, Department of Biochemistry; Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.)					

VOCATIONAL TRAINING:					
Jul 2015	C# Programing Training				
March 2014	CANdela Diagnosis Training				
Jun 2012	Trained in CANape Communication Technology. Vector Informatics GmbH Stuttgart Certificate: CANape BUS Communication Technology				
Feb 2012	Efficient Meetings Management Training				
May 2011	Extended Automation Method (EXAM) Training				
Nov 2010	dSPACE MidSize Training				
Dec 2009	Trained in HP Manual and Automatic testing tools: Win runner, Load runner, QTP,				
May 2007	Mercury Quality centre Vtechnocrat.solutions. USA Certificate Trained in Flex ray Bus Communication Technology. Vector Informatics GmbH Certificate: Flexray Bus				
Mar 2007—Apr 2007	·				
Nov 2006	Trained in CAN Bus Communication Technology. Vector Informatics GmbH Stuttgart Certificate: CAN BUS				
Jul 2006 Apr 2002 – Jul 2003	Trained in Testing and Diagnosis in a Complete Laboratory Car Trained in MOST Bus Communication Technology. Vector Informatics GmbH Trained in Networking and Systems Administration in Windows, UNIX und Novell Operating Systems. Firma Elop GmbH, Ingolstadt Germany (Diploma)				

CERTIFICATIONS:

Jul 2003 Certified Novell Administrator Netware 5 Administration (CNA)

Microsoft Certified Professional Microsoft Windows 2000 Server and Professional (MCP) May 2003—Jun 2003

Employment History:

Test Engineer

Audi AG Ingolstadt Germany

Mai/2011-----Present Electronic control unit

Test automation :Hardware-in-loop HIL Test. Audi-side-assist

- Creation of Test cases ,Function specification and Requirement engineering
- Close loop simulation EXAM Models and MATLAB/SIMULINK models with Dspace and CARTS
- System analysis using CAN-Bus, MOST-BUS, FLEXRAY –BUS and LIN Bus communications, systems Analysis tool: canoe Data analyzer Control Desk and VAS Tester
- Test cases modelling with Modelling tool EXAM
- Test execution and Defect management with KPMWEB

Enterprise Software Tester: Logistic software

Feb 2010---April 2010 **Schenker AG Austria** STAR GUI Software Interface validation

- Creation of Test cases
- Test case execution and Defect management with Clearquest

Test Engineer

AUG/2010---DEC/2010 Visteon Engineering ---Chelmsford England

Jaguar Rear Seat Entertainment System (RSE) /IPOD Features--- Apple IPOD Certification Test

- Electronic control unit Validation, System test und Diagnosis
- Creation of Test cases
- Configuration management with Doors
- Defect management with Clearquest

Jan 2008- March 2010

Firma Daimler AG--- Mercedes Benz Technology - Stuttgart

Germany Test Engineer

- BSS- Emergency Call Europe
- Creation Test cases and Test specification
- Requirement management using Doors
- Software testing and Diagnosis (System or Black-box Test) in all NTGs for BSS -ECALL Application _ Europe
- Incident Management (Faults Reporting)

Jul 2007- Dec 2007

SiemensVdo Automotive AG Regensburg Germany

Test Engineer

Ford X-Carline Project

- Electronic control unit Validation, System test und Diagnosis
- Creation of Test cases
- Configuration management with Synergy CM and Change Synergy

Nov 2006—Jun 2007

BMW AG München Germany

Test Engineer

- Electronic control unit Validation, System test und Diagnosis
- Flash-programming in I-stufe order of CAN, MOST, FLEXRAY and LIN Electronic control units from one Istufe to the other
- Complete Vehicle update with PABD and SGBD diagnostic data
- Software Logistics und Integration in I-stufe order

Jun 2006-Nov 2006

IQ-Engineering Gesellschaft/Lear Corporation GmbH Automotives Industries supplier

Test Engineer

- Black box test Amplifier (audio project for BMW) using Most bus communications system and Most Optolyzer4most professional tools.
- Static code check analysis with PC lint and QAC
- Function modelling using MATLAB/SIMULINK
- Function specification and Requirement engineering
- Function application on Prototyping system (dSPACE box)
- System analysis with simulations using MATLAB/SIMULINK
- System analysis using CAN-Bus communications systems Analysis tool canoe

Oct 2003 - Jun 2006

Solid gold Computer Solutions Freelance IT/Computer experts

Systemsadministrator

- Networking, installation and configuration of Microsoft Windows 2000 Server network
- Heterogeneous network (Novell, Microsoft windows 2000/Xp installation)
- Linux installation (room installation and network preparation)

Software Engineer

- Programming and administration of Access databank
- Software Programming with Java

Technical Summary

Elvis Fehler (fault) management tool, TCM (Test Cases Management Tool), Doors 8.0 (Requirements management Tool) Bluetooth, Peiker protocol, E-Tester, Canoe. Synergy CM, Change Synergy (Configuration management Tool), WinIdea (Software Development Tool), D.A.T.S (Diagnosis tool), Ediabas (Diagnostic tool) WINKFPT,INPA,ACM-SPY (Tracer),CVS –databank,NCS-EXPERT TOOL,EASYKFPT, NFS-TOOL, KMM-TESTTOOL (EXCELSHEET), MOST DATA-ANALYZER,Matlab, Simulink, Stateflow, CAN Bus, MOST Bus, LIN Bus, FLEXRAY Bus, PC-INT/FLEXELINT, QAC, Embedded Software Know-how QTP, HP Loadrunner, Test Director, Mercury Quality center, HP win runner,MS DOS 6.22, UNIX., Java, C/C++,

C# CSS, Jquery, HTML, Perl. Python, Oracle, MS Access KPW web. Clearquest, VAS Tester, System42, CP tools, E

Methodologies: V- Model, Waterfall Model AUTOSAR, MISRA, CMMI, SPICE, AGILE

Automation Testing Tools: Mercury Test Director, Win Runner, QTP. TPT, MATLAB, SIMULINK. STATEFLOW Dspace Control Desk CARTS, EXAM,

Languages: English, German

Interests: Playing football, cinema, music, event planning, and technology.

Reference: Available on request.